&gt;&gt; Hi and welcome to session
&gt;&gt; 大家好 欢迎大家
513.
来到 513 号会议
In this talk you will learn
本场会议中 你们将了解到
about the lower level details of
全新的高效率图像文件格式 即 HEIF
the new High Efficiency Image
中的一些底层细节
File format or HEIF and the many
同时还会了解到
advantages that this new file
这种全新的文件格式
format standard affords.
带来的诸多好处
My name is Davide Concion and I
我是 Davide Concion
manage the Image Compression
在 Apple 负责管理
Team at Apple.
图像压缩团队
During the talk, we will briefly
本次会议中 我们会简要介绍
touch upon the current de facto
目前图像压缩
standard for image compression,
使用的事实标准
a standard that everybody's
也就是大家所熟知的
familiar with JPEG.
JPEG 格式
We will go through the
我们还会介绍
requirements that Apple
在 Apple 看来 一种新的
identified as mandatory for a
图像格式应当满足
new image format.
哪些需求
We will explain why we think
还会解释 为什么我们认为
HEIF is the answer to those
HEIF 满足这些需求
requirements and we will get to
同时还会介绍
know some of the flexible tools
HEIF 所采用的
that HEIF implements.
一些功能灵活的工具
We will then present the reasons
这之后 我们会介绍
why Apple thinks HEVC is the
为什么 Apple 认为
right codec to be used within
HEIF 格式应当
the HEIF file format.
采用 HEVC 编解码器
Let's start with JPEG.
我们先来谈谈 JPEG
JPEG is still the most popular
JPEG 仍是最流行的
compression technology for
图像压缩技术
images only present on the web
可以用于网页上的图片
and on consumer electronics
也可以用于消费级
devices, such as the DSLR
电子产品 例如数码单反相机
cameras, point-and-shoot cameras
傻瓜相机
and cell phones.
和手机
Cloud services also use JPEG
云服务也使用 JPEG
because of its universal
因为它的兼容性
support.
十分强大
JPEG though has several
但 JPEG 也有很多局限
limitations, among those are the
其中之一就是
compression efficiency.
压缩效率较低
Several new compression
过去几年 人们开发了
algorithms have been developed
一些新的压缩算法
in recent years that can shrink
可以实现比 JPEG
the file size much more than
更高的压缩率
JPEG and still maintaining the
同时还能保持
same objective and subjective
图像的画质和观感
quality.
没有大的变化
Auxiliary images like alpha or
而辅助图像 例如透明度
depth are not easily supported.
和深度则很难得到 JPEG 支持
Also, in recent years new ways
并且 近年来也开发了
to present and display animated
很多呈现和显示
images have been developed.
动态图像的方法
Apple Live Photo is one of them.
Apple 的 Live Photo 便是其中之一
JPEG unfortunately does not
不幸的是 JPEG
support animation.
并不支持动态图像
Let's look at history map of
我们看一下 JPEG 和 ITU/MPEG
compression standards developed
所提出的压缩标准的
by JPEG and ITU/MPEG.
历史沿革
JPEG is really starting to show
JPEG 在当初
in its years, especially in
确实成果显著
terms of compression efficiency
尤其是在压缩效率方面
when compared to recent
即便与现在相比
advancements.
进步也相当显著
As you can see in the slide,
如幻灯片所示
JPEG has been finalized as a
JPEG 最终定型
standard in 1992, a quarter of a
成为标准 是在 1992 年
century ago.
已经是 25 年前了
Since then, several new
自那之后
compression standards have been
人们提出了一些
developed.
新的压缩标准
The latest one in the least is
最新提出的标准
HEVC.
是 HEVC
And here is HEIF for comparison
作为比较 这是 HEIF
in the timeline, which has been
在时间线上的位置
finalized in 2015.
它于 2015 年定型
Apple invested a lot of time to
Apple 花了大量时间
find a successor for JPEG and
寻找接替 JPEG 的标准
many options were evaluated.
也评估了很多选择
The requirements were extensive.
我们的需求十分广泛
The new format needs to support
新的文件格式要能支持
all the features available in
JPEG 现有的所有功能
JPEG, but at the same time
但与此同时
provide better performance.
性能表现要更为出色
It needs to be friendly to
不仅要兼容
professional photography tools,
专业摄影工具
the web and the cloud.
还要兼容网页和云
The new format also needs to be
新格式还要具备
flexible and extensible to cope
高度灵活性和可扩展性
with the ever-changing
来适应日新月异的
photography ecosystem.
摄影生态环境
Here is a list of features Apple
这张表列举了 Apple 认为
considered paramount.
是重中之重的一些特性
The compression needs to be
压缩要达到顶尖水平
state-of-the-art both on the
无论是有损压缩
[inaudible] front.
还是无损压缩
It needs to be competitive with
它既要能应对
natural images, but also when
图像文件 也要能压缩
compressing text or graphics.
文本和图形
The format needs to be friendly
这种格式要适用于
to hardware accelerated and code
现代 CPU GPU 和 ESP
and decode operations on modern
具有的硬件加速
CPUs, GPUs and ESPs.
和编解码过程
Performance and power is very
性能和表现
high in the list of
在我们的要求中
requirements.
权重是相当大的
It needs to support high depth
它还要支持高深度
and wide color gamut which is
和广色域这些
the new frontier for images
消费级设备拍摄的照片上
captured on consumer devices.
最先进的技术
It needs to be able to compress
要能够压缩
4:4:4 color sampling and also
4:4:4 的色彩采样
describe HDR content, including
也要能描述 HDR 内容
HDR metadata, transfer function
包括 HDR 元数据 传递函数
and color space definitions.
和色彩空间定义
Auxiliary images for example
至于辅助图像
alpha or depth need to have a
例如透明度和深度
commonly defined place in image
也需要在图像文件中
files.
有通用的定义空间
New editing tools will be able
新的编辑工具才能
to utilize auxiliary data for
应用辅助数据来
new presentation and editing
提供全新的呈现
experiences.
和编辑体验
In recent years, the new ways to
近几年 人们也开发了
present and display animated
新的方式来呈现
images have been developed.
和显示动态图像
Apple iPhoto is one example.
Apple 推出的 iPhoto 便是其中一例
Apple iPhoto includes animated
iPhoto 既能呈现
content together with static
动态内容 也能呈现
images.
静态图像
The new common format needs to
新的通用格式要
store animated information
能够高效存储
efficiently, ideally using
动态图像信息 理想状态下
Tempra compression techniques
要使用帧间压缩技术
and be able to instruct players
还要能指导播放器
about the presentation intention
进行呈现
for example, a looping sequence.
例如 呈现循环的序列
The new format needs also to
新格式还应该
support multiple images in the
支持同一文件内
same file.
存储多个图像
For example, multi-exposure
例如一组多重曝光的图像
stacks or stereo images.
或是立体图像
This is to aid the development
这样便可以
and implementation of new
为开发和应用
computational photography
新的计算摄影算法
algorithms.
提供帮助
Multiple representations of the
以多种方式呈现
same image matching the same
同一图像文件的功能
file are of great importance.
也非常重要
For example, multi-resolution,
例如 多分辨率呈现
including progressively
这涉及到不断地
increasing level of details or
增加细节层次
the ability to represent the
或是能够呈现
same image encoded with
由不同编解码器
different codecs.
编码的同一图像
Tiles are an important tool the
图块也是新格式
new format must implement.
必须采用的一项功能
It allows for scalable operation
这样便可以对任意大小的图片
on image of any size.
采取可缩放的操作
We'll be looking into tiles
图块相关的内容
later in the talk.
会在稍后提到
The new format needs support for
新格式还要支持
rich metadata associated to each
文件中每个图像
image in the file.
相关的丰富元数据
And also support for time meta
同时也要支持时间数据
for example, a sequence of
例如 一组照片序列
images.
包含的时间数据
There is also desire for a new
新格式还需要
format to be able to include
能够包含
other metadata types for
其他种类的元数据
example, audio or text.
例如音频或文本
Last but not least, the new
最后一点 新格式
format should be flexible and
要有灵活性和可扩展性
extensible enough to provide a
为未来开发和应用
solid foundation for the future.
打下坚实基础
We believe that HEIF is the
我们相信
answer to all these
HEIF 能够满足
requirements.
以上所有需求
What is HEIF?
什么是 HEIF
HEIF stands for High Efficiency
HEIF 是 高效图像文件
Image File Format.
的英文缩写
Version one of the spec became
第一版技术参数
an ISO standard in June of 2015.
与 2015 年六月成为 ISO 标准
Version two should be released
第二版也会
imminently.
迅速面世
A C reference model for HEIF is
HEIF 的 C 类参考样板
available upon request at this
已经公布 可以通过
link.
访问这个链接获得
The reference model is meant to
参考样板可以
provide guidance for HEIF
指导 HEIF 的应用
implementation and to understand
也能帮助了解
the specifications.
相关技术参数
As a side note, the open source
顺便一提 开源项目
project GPAC MP4Box has recently
GPAC/MP4Box 已于最近
added basic functionality to
针对 C 类文件
part C files.
提供了基本功能
The vodaworld long time ago
视频行业很久以前
learned that containers and
就认识到 容器
codes are different entities and
和编解码器是不同的实体
there are several advantages in
将二者分开
keeping them separated.
有很多好处
But historically in the image
但图像行业过去认为
world containers and codecs are
容器和编解码器
tied together and JPEG is no
应当紧密结合
exception.
JPEG 也不例外
It makes sense to make the
图像行业也要做出这样的区分
distinction in the image world
这合情合理
to get the flexibility to
因为这样才能
[inaudible].
最大化灵活性
HEIF does exactly that, it
这正是 HEIF 所做的
specifies a structural format, a
它指定了一种结构格式
container for individual images,
可以成为单张图像的容器
as well as image sequences.
也能用于图像序列
It is built on top of the widely
它的基础是广泛应用的
used ISO based media file format
ISO 基本媒体文件格式
which is based on Apple
这种格式又基于
QuickTime technologies.
Apple 的 QuickTime 技术
It also uses and enhances
它还应用并改进了
structures defined in the MP4
在 MP4 的技术参数
specification and MPEG-21
和 MPEG-21 的技术参数中
specifications.
指定的结构
Sequences for example, bursts or
各种序列 例如连拍快照和动画
animations are stored as tracks
是以轨道
or time media MP4 style.
或基于时间的媒体存储的 类似 MP4 标准
Images coded or derived are
编码图像和衍生图像
stored as items MPEG-21 style.
则以项目的形式存储 类似 MPEG-21 标准
Any compression codec can be
任何压缩编解码器
included in a HEIF container.
都能包含在 HEIF 容器中
The HEIF specification
HEIF 的技术参数中
explicitly mentions HEVC, H264
直接提及了 HEVC H.264
and JPEG in terms of file
和 JPEG 的扩展名
extensions, [inaudible] types
主类
and decoder configuration.
以及解码器配置
The basic building block of a
HEIF 文件的基本构成部分
HEIF file like the ISO based
类似 ISO 基本媒体文件格式
media file format is a data
这种数据格式
structure called box.
称为框
A box is comprised of a
框由一个
four-character type, for
四个字符的类构成
instance in the example on the
比如在右边的例子中
right the ftyp box or the
有 ftyp 框
metabox or the mdat box.
元框和 mdat 框
The size of the box in terms of
框的大小由
bytes and the payload of the
框的字节数和载荷
box.
所决定
The metabox gives a full
元框完整描述了
description of what is included
这一文件内
in the file.
包含的全部内容
The handler type of the metabox
元框的处理器类型
for whomever is familiar with
如果有人熟悉 ISO 基本媒体文件格式的话
ISOBMFF specification is of type
应该清楚 元框的处理器类型
PICT indicating to a reader that
是 PICT  读取器便理解为
this metabox handles images.
这个元框处理的是图像
Before going into the anatomy of
在深入探讨 HEIF 文件
a HEIF file a note on file
的结构之前 先来谈谈
extensions.
文件的扩展名
The standard defines explicitly
标准明确规定
the file extension of a HEIF
HEIF 文件的扩展名
file depending on the particular
依压缩单张图片
codec being used to compress
或图片序列
single images or sequences.
的编解码器而定
The list of extensions can be
所有可能的扩展名
found in the table above.
都能在这张表中找到
iOS 11 can capture and store
iOS 11 可以拍摄并存储
HEIF images using the HEVC
HEIF 图像 使用的
codec.
是 HEVC 编解码器
Therefore, the extension you
因此 你们经常遇到的扩展名
will be encountering is .HEIC.
会是 .HEIC
In iOS 11 and macOS 10.13 we
在 iOS 11 和 macOS 10.13 中
support all three single image
我们支持全部三种
HEIF flavors for decoding and
HEIF 文件的解码
displaying.
以及显示
Note also that a HEIF file that
请注意 如果 HEIF 文件
includes sequences will have a
包含序列 那么
different extension than a HEIF
它的扩展名
that contains only single
会与只包含单张图像
images.
的 HEIF 文件有所不同
We will now dive into the HEIF
我们现在就来详细了解
format and its anatomy.
HEIF 文件及其结构
Let's start with the concept of
首先先来谈谈
item.
项这个概念
Every element in a HEIF file is
HEIF 文件中 每一个元素
an item.
就是一个项
There can be coded items for
项包括编码项
instance, HEVC encoded frame or
如 HEVC 编码的帧
tiles.
或图块
There can be derived items for
还有派生项
instance, an image overlay or an
如图像叠加
image grid.
或图像栅格
There can be metadata items for
也有元数据项
instance, EXIF, XMP or MPEG-7
例如 EXIF XMP 或 MPEG-7
metadata.
的元数据
Each item can also come with
每个项也有
several properties associated to
与之相关联的
it.
几个属性
Everything is then connected via
由此 一切联系都通过
structures that link certain
将项与其他项或属性
items to other items or
相互连接的结构
properties.
来实现
Images are items and because
图像也是项
multiple images can be stored in
又因为多张图片
the same file the HEIF standard
能存储在一个文件内
differentiates between them by
HEIF 标准通过
assigning certain roles.
分配不同角色将其区分
Some of the roles specified in
HEIF 标准规定了一些角色
HEIF are listed in the table
这些角色都能在
above.
这张表中找到
The primary recovery image is
主图像 或称封面图像
the representative image of a
是一个文件的
file.
代表图像
The primary image should be
主图像应当在
displayed when no other
播放器无法获取
information is possible or
或解码其他信息
decodable by a player.
的时候显示
Only one primary image can be
一个 HEIF 文件
present in a HEIF file.
只能存在一个主图像
Other full-resolution images in
HEIF 文件中
HEIF files are called master
其他的原分辨率图像
images.
称为原图像
The thumbnail is a small
文件的缩略图
resolution representation of a
即是低分辨率的
master image.
原图像
Multiple thumbnails can be
一个 HEIF 文件
stored in a HEIF for example,
可以存储多个
with different sizes.
不同尺寸的缩略图
It's a very useful feature for
这对超高分辨率图像的
progressive decoding and
渐进解码
displaying very high-resolution
以及显示
images.
大有帮助
The auxiliary image is an image
辅助图像是指
that complements a master image.
补充原图像的图像
For example, an alpha plane or a
例如透明度层
depth map.
或深度映射
Auxiliary images can assist in
辅助图像可以在
displaying master images, but
辅助显示原图像
are not typically displayed.
但一般不显示
A hidden image is an image that
隐藏图像是指
should never be displayed.
永远不应显示的图像
It can be present in the file
它可以在文件中
for example, as an input image
以输入图像
of a derived image.
或派生图像的形式存在
iOS 11 HEIF implementation uses
iOS 11 对 HEIF 的应用中
extensively hidden images which
大量使用了隐藏图像
are called tiles.
称为图块
Each tile is used to compose the
每个图块都用来
final master or canvas image.
显示最终的原图像或成品图像
Now derived manager is an image
派生图像
that is rendered by an indicated
是指对特定输入图像
operation being performed on
进行特定操作
other input images.
渲染得到的结果
For instance, the canvas image
例如 此前提到的
described before is rendered
成品图像便是
after stitching together
拼接不同图块后
multiple tiles.
渲染得到的
Equivalent images are
等价图像是指
alternative images for instance,
可用于替换的图像
encoded with a different codec.
可以用不同的编解码器编码得到
A server could distribute the
服务器可以将
same input content to players
相同的输入内容
that may have different decoding
分发给解码能力不同的
capabilities.
播放器
Once the role has been defined
一旦每张图片
for each image properties can be
都有了对应的角色
associated to them.
便可赋予其相关联的属性
Properties are either
属性可以是描述性的
descriptive or transformative.
也可以是编辑性的
They can also be essential for
可以是必需的
example, the codec
例如编解码器的
initialization info or
初始化信息
nonessential.
也可以是非必需的
The table above provides a
这张表列举了了
non-exhaustive list of
HEIF 文件中
descriptive properties for
图像具有的
images inside a HEIF file.
部分描述性属性
All the usual suspect
这里可以找到
information can be found in
最常见的一些信息
there like the image size, the
例如图像尺寸
color information, the type of
颜色信息
auxiliary image which can be
辅助图像
alpha or depth and also the
如透明度和深度 还有
configuration parameters to
编解码器初始化的
initialize the decoder.
一些配置参数
The table above provides a
这张表中
non-exhaustive list of
则列举了部分
transformative properties.
编辑性属性
The presence of these properties
这些属性
instructs a HEIF [inaudible]
能够告诉 HEIF 分析器
that the image needs to go
图像需要经过
through extra steps before being
一些额外修改
displayed.
才能最终显示
For example, the clean aperture
例如 清除光圈
property instructs a HEIF reader
这一属性会告诉 HEIF 读取器
that the crop operation must be
必须先裁剪图像
performed before rending the
再对图像进行
final image.
最后渲染
All the properties for each
每张图像的所有属性
image are grouped together in
都包括在同一个
the same item property box.
名为属性框的项目中
Each image can then be
借此 每张图片
associated to which property via
都可以通过属性框
the association box.
来关联属性
We will use an example to
我们会用一个例子
describe how the association
来描述关联属性
works.
是如何工作的
The above HEIF container on the
左边的 HEIF 容器
left describes the file with one
表示这个文件
main image and one thumbnail.
包括一个主图像和一个缩略图
The main image is comprised of
主图像又由
four tiles.
四个图块组成
The item property box or ipco
项属性框 即 ipco 框
box contains all the decoder
包含所有解码器配置
configuration and the sizes of
还包含着
the main image, the tiles and
主图像 图块
the thumbnails.
和缩略图的尺寸数据
Note that the order matters for
请注意 这个框中
this box.
顺序是有意义的
The association box or ipma box
右边的关联框 即 ipma 框
on the right groups properties
将所有属性
nicely based on their position
按照位置
with the item ID in the file.
与文件中的项 ID 关联
As explained before, there is a
如前所述
total of six items in the file,
这个文件中共有六个项
one image, four tiles and one
一个图像 四个图块
thumbnail.
和一个缩略图
Items 1 through 4 are the tiles,
项 1 至 4 是图块
these are hidden images with
是隐藏图像
properties in position one, the
属性是位置 1
decoder configuration and
即解码器配置
position two, the size which is
和位置 2  即尺寸
500 by 500 pixel.
为 500 x 500 像素
Item five is the main image,
项 5 为 主图像
only the size property is
只具有尺寸属性
defined since this is this is a
因为这是一个
derived image.
派生图像
The size is 1,000 by 1,000
它的尺寸
pixels.
为 1000 x 1000 像素
Next, we will briefly talk about
接下来 我们会简要谈一下
image sequences in HEIF.
HEIF 中的图像序列
When sequences are embedded in a
嵌入序列的 HEIF 文件
HEIF file the move box and it's
包含 moov 框
sub boxes are also present in
和 moov 框的分框
the file.
等框体
The move boxes fully described
moov 框的完整定义
in the ISO MP4 file format
包含在 ISO MP4 文件格式
specification from which HEIF
的技术参数中
derives.
HEIF 便是由此而来
Each sequence of images or
每个图像或取样的序列
samples is described via the
都由 trak 框描述
trak box where all the timing
其中包含了播放轨道
information to play back the
所需要的一切
track is included.
时间信息
HEIF specifies a new track
HEIF 规定了一个全新的
handler for picture called pict.
处理图像的轨道处理器 称为 pict.
The key difference is that while
主要区别在于
the timing information given for
音频或视频
a video or an audio track is
包含的时间信息
used to synchronize the playback
能够用于同步播放进度
the timing information an image
图像序列轨道
sequence track can represent
包含的时间信息则能够代表
either the capture time for
连拍快照的拍摄时间
example, a burst or the
或是派生幻灯片中
suggested display time for
每个单张图像
example, to derive a slideshow.
建议的显示时间
Roles can be used for image
也可以为图像序列
sequences to.
指定角色
For example, a HEIF file could
例如  HEIF 文件
embed a track of thumbnails or a
内嵌缩略图轨道
track of auxiliary images
或辅助图像轨道
associated with the master
并与原图像轨道
track.
相关联
One of the most important HEIF
HEIF 最重要的特性之一
features is the ability to
就是能在文件中
control the playback by
嵌入创造者的指令
signaling in the file the intent
并以此来实现
of the creator.
对播放的控制
For example, an edit list
例如 编辑列表
enables modifying the playback
能够改变每个采样的
order and pace of each sample.
播放顺序和速度
HEIF also allows indicating edit
HEIF 还允许
list repetitions for example,
编辑列表的重复
for looping animations.
可以实现循环动画等功能
The repetition can be indicated
重复的次数
to last for a certain duration
可以为特定值
or be infinite.
也可以无限重复
Given that the ISO tracks can be
由于 HEIF 中
used in HEIF files interframe
轨道符合 ISO 标准
prediction is also available.
便可以实现帧间预测
Inter prediction is the ability
帧间预测是指
to remove coded information by
移除部分编码信息
predicting the content of the
而通过此前
current frame from similar
或之后的相似帧
frames in the past or in the
来进行预测
future.
并生成当前帧
This gives a tremendous
这一点
advantage in terms of
对于压缩
compression.
意义非凡
Inter prediction can also
帧间预测也能
introduce a delay decode time
延缓解码时间
because the previous frames must
因为必须
be decoded first before being
先解码前一帧
able to decode the current
才能够解码
frame.
当前帧
HEIF allows inter prediction,
HEIF 允许帧间预测
but also includes constraints in
但也在文件中
the file to limit frame
限制了帧与帧的
interdependencies.
相互依赖
For instance, each predicted
比方说
image can be restricted to point
每一个预测生成的图像
only to unknown predicted image
都只能指向已经预测生成的图像
or inter.
即内部帧
In this case, the time to decode
如此一来 解码序列中
each frame in a sequence becomes
每一帧的时间
deterministic.
就可以预先确定
Last but not least, a HEIF image
最后一点  HEIF 图像
can be subdivided into tiles.
可以分割成不同图块
Tiles are rectangular regions
图块是指图像中的
within an image.
长方形区域
They are completely independent
它们在 HEIF 文件中
items in a HEIF file and they
是完全独立的项
can be of different or same
尺寸可以相同
size.
也可以不同
If their size is different a
如果尺寸不同
relative location property
那么相对位置属性
describes their position in the
便可以描述它们
final image.
在最终图像中所处的位置
If their size is the same the
如果尺寸相同
final image is described as a
那么最终图像便会以
grid. Several reasons why tiles
栅格的形式描述 因为以下几点
make HEIF extremely flexible.
图块使得 HEIF 高度灵活
A player can exploit parallelism
播放器可以充分利用并行处理
and decode time.
缩减解码时间
For example, each tile can be
比方说 每个图块
separately and independently
都可以分别
decoded.
且单独解码
Tiles can be used to reduce
图块可以降低改变图片尺寸
memory consumption when resizing
所需的内存大小
an image rather than decoding
因为无需解码
the whole much and then apply a
整张图片之后
rescale operation each tile can
再进行操作 每个图块
be independently decoded and
都能单独解码
rescaled and then placed in a
并改变大尺寸 再置于
smaller buffer for rendering.
较小的缓存中进行渲染
Cropping becomes very fast
裁剪图像速度也很快
because a player does not need
因为播放器不需要
to decode the whole image to
解码整个图像
extract a certain region.
再提取特定区域
This property is extremely
这一属性
useful for zooming operation.
在缩放操作中也格外有用
For instance, a gigapixel image
例如 一张数十亿像素的图像
could be decoded and displayed
可以轻而易举地解码 显示
and zoomed in with ease without
放大 而不需要
the need to decode the whole
解码整张图像
image into a multi gigabit
并占用数十亿位的
buffer.
缓存
Of note, the tiles can be used
同时 图块还可以
also as an encoding tool.
用作编码工具
A smart encoder can make
智能编码器
different decision based on the
可以根据图块内容的不同
content of each tile.
做出不同选择
Apple HEIF implementation uses
Apple 在使用 HEIF 的过程中
tiles extensively.
大量使用了图块
Note though that the HEVC
但要注意  HEVC 的技术参数
specification also supports
同样支持
subdividing a frame into tiles
将每帧分成图块
as a parallelization tool.
用作并行处理
Apple does not use tiles in HEVC
Apple 对图块的应用
parlance, but rather each tile
并非按照 HEVC 的规定 而是每个图块
is a whole HEVC frame, we call
都是一个完整的 HEVC 帧
them system tiles.
我们称其为系统图块
Next, we will talk about HEVC,
接下来 我们谈谈 HEVC
the codec Apple has chosen to
也是 Apple 用来压缩
compress HEIF photos.
HEIF 照片的编解码器
Two of the major reasons for
选择 HEVC
selecting HEVC.
有两大原因
First, HEVC is the latest
首先 HEVC
technology in the compression
是压缩标准领域
standard world.
最先进的技术
With HEVC we see an average of
在画质相同的情况下
2X compression compared to JPEG
HEVC 的压缩率平均
containing the same visual
是 JPEG 压缩率
quality.
的两倍
Second, HEVC hardware support is
第二 HEVC 开始得到
becoming available in most CPUs
绝大多数 CPU
and GPUs.
和 GPU 的硬件支持
For instance, HEVC hardware
例如 Intel 的第六代
support is available from the
Core 处理器就包含
sixth generation Intel core
对 HEVC 的
processors.
硬件支持
This means except means
这意味着
exceptional performance without
表现出众
sacrificing battery life.
而不需要牺牲续航时间
Several inter coding tools have
一些帧内编码工具
been added to the standard that
也加入到了标准之中
allow HEVC to outperform JPEG.
使得 HEVC 的表现超过了 JPEG
In the next few slides we will
接下来的几张幻灯片
mention some.
会提到一些
You will notice that the common
你会注意到
theme here is flexibility.
我们总会讲到灵活性
First, the block size.
首先是区块尺寸
JPEG divides each image into a
JPEG 将图像分割成
grid of blocks of 8 by 8 pixels.
由 8 x 8 像素的区块构成的栅格
These blocks are then described
接下来 这些区块被描述
transformed and quantized.
转化和量化
HEVC has the flexibility of
HEVC 的灵活性
being able to divide an image in
使其能将图像
blocks that are 64 by 64 pixels
划分为大至 64 x 64 像素
down to 4 by 4 pixels.
小至 4 x 4 像素的区块
The transform size is also
也可以在区块内部
flexible within the block.
灵活转换尺寸
A new optional discrete
标准新增了
[inaudible] transform has been
离散尺寸转换功能
added to the standard and three
作为可选项
possible scanning orders are
还为编码系数的编组
available to group coded
增加了三种可用的
coefficients.
扫描顺序
Next, the block prediction.
接下来是区块预测
JPEG allows the top left corner
JPEG 支持预测 8 x 8 大小区块
coefficient also called the DC
左上角的系数
component or the constant
这一系数又称 DC 分量
component of an 8 by 8 block to
或恒定分量
be predicted from the block on
依据则是这一区块
the left.
左侧的区块
HEVC adds the flexibility to
HEVC 又增加了
predict every pixel value within
在区块内部预测每一个像素值
a block.
的功能
Up to 35 angular predictions are
角度预测范围
available.
最多可达 35 种
Being able to remove redundant
还可以运用
information in a block by
相邻区块中
exploiting similar information
包含的相似信息
available in neighboring blocks
来消除冗余信息
is one of the most efficient
这也是 HEVC 内置的
tools inside HEVC.
高效工具之一
Entropy coding.
下一项是熵编码
JPEG uses Huffman coding as the
JPEG 使用 Huffman 编码
engine for statistical encoding.
作为统计编码的引擎
The idea is to assign variable
这是为了将
length codes to input
可变长编码
coefficient.
赋值给输入的系数
With shorter length codes
赋给系数的长编码
assigned to coefficients with
长度越短
higher frequency.
效率也越高
HEVC on the other hand, employs
而 HEVC 则是采用
an arithmetic coder called CABAC
一种算法编码器 称为 CABAC
which stands for Context
是 上下文参考
Adaptive Binary Arithmetic
二进制算术编码
Coding.
的缩写
CABAC is notable for providing
CABAC 因
much better compression than
压缩率显著高于
most other entropy encoding
其他大多数熵编码算法
algorithms.
而知名
Quantization.
下一项是量化
Quantization is a [inaudible] C
量化是一项有损
compression technique achieved
压缩技术 通过
by compressing a range of values
压缩一个取值范围
to a single quantum value.
为单一量化值而实现
JPEG utilizes global
JPEG 对每个
quantization matrixes for each 8
8 x 8 的区块使用全局
by 8 block.
量化矩阵
HEVC on top of the quantization
HEVC 则在量化矩阵之上
matrix adds the flexibility of
增进了灵活性 添加了
assigning a different
为每个区块
quantization parameter for each
赋不同的量化参数
block.
的功能
This allows smart encoding
这样一来 智能编码算法
algorithms to compress more
就能压缩更多
areas of an image while the
图像上更多的区域
human visual system is less
而人类视觉系统
susceptible to detect artifacts.
就更难捕捉到人为差异
For instance, high-frequency
例如 频率高的
content.
内容
Next is the blocking, a tool
再接下来是去除区块边界
that is available only in HEVC.
这项工具仅有 HEVC 支持
Blocking artifacts are visible
人工边界是指
discontinuities occurring at
区块边缘可见的
block boundaries.
不连续区域
The HEVC deblocking filter is a
HEVC 包含去区块滤波器
filter applied to the pixels
这种滤波器应用于
around the block edges to
区块边缘的像素
smoothen the transition and get
使过度更平滑
more pleasing visual results.
视觉效果也更好
SAO which stands for Sample
SAO  也就是
Adaptive Offset is an extra
取样自适应偏移 是
filtering step available in HEVC
HEVC 中一道额外的滤波器
that is applied to the output of
应用于去区块滤波器
the deblocking filter to further
作用的结果 来进一步
improve the quality.
改善图像质量
It's a local filter that can
这是一种局部滤波器 能够
attenuate bringing artifacts or
减弱边缘振荡效应
changes in sample intensity of
在图片的某些区域
some areas of a picture for a
改变取样密度
better visual quality.
以提升画质
Both these techniques allow for
这两项技术都能
more pleasing images, especially
使图像更赏心悦目
when the compression is very
尤其是压缩率很高
high.
的时候
We have gone through several
我们已经讲了很多
HEIF and HEVC features and
HEIF 和 HEVC 的特性
tools, I wanted to take a second
和工具 我想再花一点时间
to mention a few characteristics
讲一讲 iOS 11
of HEIF files captured on iOS
拍摄的 HEIF 文件
11.
的一些特点
First, the extension for HEIF
首先  iOS 11 上
images captured with iOS 11 will
拍摄的图像 扩展名
be .HEIC because of the HEVC
为 .HEIC  因为使用了 HEVC
codec.
作编解码器
The HEVC profile utilized to
用于压缩图像的
compress images is the main
HEVC 配置文件
still profile.
是主静止配置
Also, we use HEVC monochrome
我们还使用 HEVC 的
profile for depth data.
单色配置文件处理深度数据
Images are encoded using tiles
图像使用 512 x 512 像素
that are 512 by 512 pixels.
的区块进行编码
They are positioned in a grid
区块以栅格的形式
fashion to cover the whole
进行定位 覆盖
image.
整个图像
The thumbnail is a 320 by 240
缩略图为 320 x 240 像素
image HEVC encoded.
的图像 用 HEVC 编码
It is four times the size of a
是常见 160 x 120 像素大小
common 160 by 120 JPEG thumbnail
JPEG 缩略图的四倍
and this is to help showing
这有助于在高像素密度
better thumbnail quality when
的现代显示屏上
images are displayed on modern
显示图像时 呈现
screens with high pixel density.
更高的缩略图画质
EXIF metadata is part of the
EXIF 元数据也包含在
HEIF file like JPEG for backward
HEIF 文件中 像 JPEG 一样
compatibility.
以确保向后兼容性
Depth data is stored as an
深度数据以
auxiliary image and the metadata
辅助图像的形式存储
pertinent to depth is stored as
相关元数据存储在
XMP payload associated with the
与深度图像相关联的
depth image.
XMP 载荷中
Last, a note about file
最后 讲一下
creation.
文件生成
The HEIF standard does not
HEIF 标准没有
mandate any order for the boxes
读取器在文件顶层
a reader could find at the top
读取框体的
level of a HEIF file, but we
顺序 但我们
found that ordering them in a
发现 排列成特定顺序
certain way greatly helps
能够极大帮助
parsers and decoders.
分析器和解码器
For example, having the
比方说
thumbnail early in the file
让缩略图排位靠前
would allow parsing and display
可以分析并显示
huge amount of HEIF images
大量 HEIF 图像
without the need to parse the
而不需要先分析
whole file.
整个文件
For [inaudible] transmission or
为实现高速传输
web application once the metabox
或网页应用 一旦接受到元框
is received all the information
那么就可以获取
for the file is available and
文件的全部信息
therefore readers can start
读取器就可以
configuring the decoding and
配置解码器和
display pipelines before having
显示过程 而不需要
received the whole coded data.
获取完整的编码数据
Let's summarize what we have
让我们来总结一下
learned today.
今天讲到的内容
The photography world needs a
摄影界需要一种
better image file format to
更好的图像文件格式
replace the rather old JPEG.
来取代垂垂老矣的 JPEG
We looked at the extensive list
我们逐一分析了
of requirements that Apple
Apple 认为
considered paramount when
寻找 JPEG 替代品
searching for a JPEG
最为重要的
replacement.
一些要求
We believe HEIF is the answer
我们相信 HEIF
for all the requirements.
能够满足全部这些要求
Its flexibility allows to handle
它灵活性极高
with ease and elegance the
能高效 简洁地
advancements available in iOS 11
运用 iOS 11 技术上的进步
and its extensibility also
它的可扩展性又能
allows HEIF to be a solid
让 HEIF 为未来开发运用
foundation for the future.
打下坚实基础
We then analyzed the various
我们后来分析了
features available in the HEIF
HEIF 标准的
standard.
一些特性
And finally, we looked at the
最后 我们介绍了
HEVC tools that make it the best
让其成为不二之选的
choice, both in terms of
HEVC 工具 既包括
compression efficiency and
提升压缩效率的 还包括
friendliness toward hardware
对硬件架构友好
architecture for performance and
能够提升表现
power.
和性能的
For more information, please
要了解更多信息
visit the URL for the High
请访问第 513 号会议
Efficiency Image File format
“High Efficiency Image File format（高效率图像文件格式）”
session 513.
的网址
And if you're still at the show
如果你继续参与 WWDC
we invite you to visit the two
我们欢迎你参加
related sessions about HEIF and
与 HEIF 和 HEVC 有关的
HEVC.
两场会议
Thank you for watching the talk
感谢观看本场会议
and enjoy the rest of WWDC 2017.
祝你在 WWDC 2017 过得愉快